A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Medical Interests, Series K FA320
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Health Agencies
  - Health Agencies - Citizen's Health Committee on Neighborhood Health Development, 1941-1943, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    To inform public of health services. John D. Rockefeller 3rd contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard.
    137.1
  - Health Agencies - United States Public Health Service - Subcommittee for Civilian Cooperation, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    Branch of hygiene work directed to fighting venereal disease in armed forces during World War I. Based on cooperation with the federal government. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. referred matter to Rockefeller Foundation and Bureau of Social Hygiene; agreed to make small monthly gifts. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s attitude toward publicity about venereal disease fight. Major W. F. Snow's Reports. USO's 1943 objectives. Correspondents include W. H. Zinnser, Jerome D. Greene, Major W. F. Snow, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Health Agencies - United States Public Health Service - Council of National Defense - Major Snow, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Health Agencies - United States Public Health Service - Subcommittee for Civilian Cooperation, 1920, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Health Agencies - Department of Health - New York, 1912-1913, 1918, 1920-1923, 1933, 1942-1947, 1956-1957, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    Contributions through Rockefeller Brothers Fund. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Martha Baird Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
    137.3
  - Health Agencies - Department of Health - New York - American Museum of Health, 1939-1941, 1947-1950 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    Museum at Hunter college. Mayor LaGuardia asks Rockefellers to support organization; declined.
  - Health Agencies - Department of Health - New York - Baby Week, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Health Agencies - Public Health Research Institute of New York City, 1941-1950, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    Research on infectious diseases; city supported. No Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    137.4
  - Health Agencies - Public Health Research Institute of New York City, 1941-1950, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 0059A)
    David Rockefeller a vice president for a short time. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Health Agencies - Public Health Research Institute of New York City - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    Establishment of a Department of Psychopharmacology at Institute. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, David Heyman, David F. Freeman.
  - Health Agencies, 1947-1955 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    Appeals to members of the family for aid in various health programs; declined. Arthur Jones' participation in attempt to outline plan for national medical care, 1950. Laurance S. Rockefeller gift to National Paraplegia Foundation.
    137.5
  - Health Agencies, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    Appeals to members of the family for aid in various health programs; declined. Arthur Jones' participation in attempt to outline plan for national medical care, 1950. Laurance S. Rockefeller gift to National Paraplegia Foundation,$50,00.
  - Health Agencies - National Publicity Council, 1943-1944, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Health Agencies - Miscellaneous, 1946-1949 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Health Agencies - Miscellaneous, 1950-1958 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Health Agencies - Miscellaneous, 1958-1961 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Health Agencies - Health Council of Greater New York, 1945-1950 (Box 9, Folder 67)
    Study of health needs in New York City; group to coordinate various health agencies. By-laws, incorporation. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.
    137.6
  - Health Agencies - Health Council of Greater New York - Committee on Nursing Services for Civilian Defense, 1950-1951 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Health Agencies - National Health Council, 1946-1958 (Box 9, Folder 69)
    National Health Fund; Alan Gregg Fund. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, Philip E. Ryan.
    137.7
  - Health Agencies - National Arthritis Research Foundation, 1946, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 70)
    Invitations to dinner, declined. Correspondents include Spyros P. Skouras.
    137.8
  - Health Agencies - Medical Memorial Fund, Inc., 1942, 1944, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    Organization to investigate needs and support medical research. Planned to siphon off some of the money spent on funeral flowers. Not successful apparently; no Rockefeller contribution. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.
    137.9
  - Health Agencies - National League for Nursing/National Organization for Public Health Nursing, 1935-1936, 1945-1954, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 72)
    Contributions by Mary French Rockefeller ($25 annually); Mary Clark Rockefeller.
    137.10
  - Health Agencies - Cerebral Palsy - Miscellaneous Organizations and Treatment, 1947-1955, 1959-1961 (Box 9, Folder 73)
    Invitations to activities, declined. Laurance S. Rockefeller contribution. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Harold Lunn, Anita Colby.
    137.11
  - Health Agencies - National Mental Health Foundation, 1946-1949 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    To improve the care of the mentally ill; backed up Dr. Rufus M. Jones. Rockefeller Foundation contribution, 1947; later requests for aid declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Rufus M. Jones.
    137.12
  - Health Agencies - National Mental Health Foundation, 1946-1949 (Box 9, Folder 0074A)
    Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Health Agencies - New York Heart Association, 1945-1961 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    Requests to members of family for aid and support. Some contributions; annual contribution by Abby Rockefeller Mauz, 1947-1960. Correspondents include Abby Rockefeller Mauz, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Thomas Dewey.
    137.13
  - Health Agencies - New York Heart Association, 1945-1961 (Box 9, Folder 0075A)
  - Health Agencies - National Multiple Sclerosis Society, 1947-1960 (Box 10, Folder 76)
    History of society; list of family's contributions, 1948-1959. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    137.14
  - Health Agencies - National Multiple Sclerosis Society - David Rockefeller, 1955-1956, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 77)
    Invitation to become chairman of 1955 campaign; declined. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, David Rockefeller.
  - Health Agencies - National Multiple Sclerosis Society - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1952, 1955-1956 (Box 10, Folder 78)
    Request for contribution by personal friend, Mrs. T. E. Camp. No contributions made.
  - Health Agencies - National Multiple Sclerosis Society - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1946-1949, 1952-1961 (Box 10, Folder 79)
    Contributions made on non-recurring basis. Death of Alan Ryder Breed, classmate of Laurance S. Rockefeller at Princeton, of multiple sclerosis. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Arthur Jones, Mrs. Richard Storrs, William C. Breed, Francis L. Waitmarsh.
  - Health Agencies - New York Diabetes Association, Inc., 1947-1948, 1951, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 80)
    To educate public on medical care for diabetes. Asked Nelson A. Rockefeller to be honorary patron of New York Diabetes Association; declined.
    137.15
  - Health Agencies - Muscular Dystrophy Association of America, 1950-1960 (Box 10, Folder 81)
    To inform public and promote research. Mary French Rockefeller contribution. correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Arthur Jones, Mary French Rockefeller.
    137.17
  - Health Agencies - Virginia Council on Health and Medical Care, 1946, 1950, 1952-1961 (Box 10, Folder 82)
    $3,000 contribution by Winthrop Rockefeller. Correspondents include Arthur Jones, Edgar J. Fisher, Carlisle H. Humelsine.
    137.18
  - Health Agencies - International Society for Rehabilitation of Disabled, 1953-1961 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    Formerly International Society for the Welfare of Cripples. American Korean Foundation program. David Rockefeller gifts, Mary French Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Arthur Jones, Howard Rusk, David Rockefeller.
    137.19
  - Health Agencies - People to People Health Foundation, Inc., 1959-1961 (Box 10, Folder 84)
    "Project Hope" Navy hospital ship in Far East. John D. Rockefeller 3rd's contribution. Correspondents include David Freeman, William Walsh, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    137.20
  - Health Agencies - Allergy Foundation of America, 1954, 1956-1958 (Box 10, Folder 85)
    Also American Foundation for Allergic Diseases. Edwin S. Webster Jr. Memorial Fund; Laurance S. Rockefeller's interest, contributions; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Raymond B. Fosdick contribution. Correspondents include Charles D. Marple, David Freeman, Arthur Jones, Horace Baldwin, Russell Ziegler, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dana S. Creel.
    137.51
  - Health Agencies - Allergy Foundation of America, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - Health Agencies - Arthritis and Rheumatism Foundation, 1948-1960 (Box 11, Folder 87)
    Research organization. Some contributions; Rockefeller Brothers Fund made grants totalling $9,000; discontinued in 1956. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Paul Holbrook, John Corley.
    137.81
  - Health Agencies - Westchester Cerebral Palsy Association, 1946-1959 (Box 11, Folder 88)
    Association to collect funds for research and referral clinic. Later requests declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Willard Simpkins.
    137.111
  - Health Agencies - Westchester Cerebral Palsy Association, 1946-1959 (Box 11, Folder 0088A)
    David Rockefeller's single contribution. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
  - Health Agencies - United Cerebral Palsy, 1950-1961 (Box 11, Folder 89)
    Many requests for participation; declined. Rockefeller Brothers Fund grant. Correspondents include Roger Firestone, Dana S. Creel, Thomas S. Nichols.
    137.112
  - Health Agencies - United Cerebral Palsy, 1950-1961 (Box 11, Folder 0089A)
    Contributions by David Rockefeller.
  - Health Agencies - United Cerebral Palsy Research and Educational Foundation, 1955-1956, 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 90)
    Roger Firestone asks for Laurance S. Rockefeller's participation; declined.
  - Health Agencies - United Cerebral Palsy - New York City, 1950-1961 (Box 11, Folder 91)
    Promotion of research, provide information, etc. Laurance S. Rockefeller gift. No real interest shown. Correspondents include Arthur Jones, Peter Grimm, Percy J. Ebbott.
    137.113
  - Health Agencies - United Cerebral Palsy - New York City, 1950-1961 (Box 11, Folder 0091A)
    David Rockefeller's contribution.
  - Health Agencies - National Association for Mental Health, 1950-1961 (Box 12, Folder 92)
    Contributions from family members; Rockefeller Brothers Fund contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dana S. Creel, Arthur Bunker, Orin Root, Marka DuPont.
    137.121
  - Health Agencies - New York Mental Health Fund, 1954-1955 (Box 12, Folder 93)
    Request for aid, declined.
    137.122
  - Health Agencies - Mental Health Miscellaneous, 1958-1961 (Box 12, Folder 94)
    Mrs. Godfrey Rockefeller originates Research In Schizophrenia Endowment. Correspondents include Helen G. Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Mrs. Julian Street Jr., Edward L. Love.
    137.123
  - Health Agencies - Mental Health Miscellaneous, 1958-1961 (Box 12, Folder 0094A)
    David Rockefeller gift to Staten Island Mental Health Society.
  - Health Agencies - Tappan Zee Mental Health Center, Inc., 1955-1961 (Box 12, Folder 95)
    137.127
  - Health Agencies - American Heart Association, 1947-1961 (Box 12, Folder 96)
    Invitation to participate, declined. Correspondents include A. W. Robertson, Arthur Jones, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    137.131
  - Health Agencies - American Heart Association, 1947-1961 (Box 12, Folder 0096A)
  - Health Agencies - Westchester Heart Association, 1948-1961 (Box 12, Folder 97)
    Requests for aid, declined.
  - Philippines - Leonard Wood Memorial for the Eradication of Leprosy, 1925-1957 (Box 12, Folder 98)
    David McAlpin's interest in organization. 1929 campaign, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes $100,000. Other requests declined. Correspondents include Arthur Woods, Thomas B. Appleget, David McAlpin, Perry Burgess.
    160
  - Philippines - Leonard Wood Memorial for the Eradication of Leprosy - Pledge, June 14, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 99)
    Leonard Wood Memorial contribution, $100,000.
  - Madame Curie Radium Fund - Radium Institute, Warsaw, 1921-1935 (Box 12, Folder 100)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. orders "Memorial" to make gift to buy radium for Curie Paris institute. Request from Belgrade for radium for clinic there; Request from M. Curie for radium to be used at Warsaw Institute, refused. Later John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $10,000 toward gift of gram of radium for Madame Curie personally. Correspondents include Madame Curie, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    134
- Mental Hygiene
  - National Committee on Mental Hygiene, 1909-1950 (Box 12, Folder 101)
    Created in 1909 to prevent insanity and care for the insane; grew out of a book by C. W. Beers. Work of the committee. Supported by Rockefeller Foundation; individual assistance by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 25th anniversary of work. Later form requests for aid declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, C. W. Beers, Thomas Salmon, MD.
    69
  - National Committee on Mental Hygiene - C. W. Beer's Book, "A Mind That Found Itself", 1907-1911 (Box 13, Folder 102)
    Autobiography of recovered mental patient; used to start interest in Committee for Mental Hygiene; brought to F. T. Gates' attention. No action in this folder. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, C. W. Beers.
  - National Committee on Mental Hygiene - T. W. Salmon Memorial, 1929-1941 (Box 13, Folder 103)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes to Memorial to Dr. Salmon. Lecture series. Declines assistance to son of doctor. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
  - National Committee on Mental Hygiene - Jonzel Foundation, Inc., 1958-1961 (Box 13, Folder 104)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions.
- Narcotics
  - Narcotic Drugs, 1923-1929, 1932, 1937, 1939-1940 (Box 13, Folder 105)
    Succession of committees and individuals devoted to ending narcotic trade and addiction. Small contributions made by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include E. S. Bishop, C. H. Brent, Mrs. Hamilton Wright, William McAdoo, Fred H. Allen.
    9
  - Narcotic Drugs - World Narcotic Defense Association, 1931-1935 (Box 13, Folder 106)
    Requests for contributions, refused. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Arthur Woods.
  - Narcotic Drugs - R. P. Hobson, 1924-1928 (Box 13, Folder 107)
    Requests for aid in struggle against narcotics addiction; refused because of interest and contributions in other areas of field. Correspondents include R. P. Hobson.
  - Narcotics, 1959-1961 (Box 13, Folder 108)
  - Narcotic Drugs - Boys and Girls Anti-Cigarette League, 1922-1931 (Box 13, Folder 109)
    Small John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions.
    9.1
- New York Academy of Medicine
  - New York Academy of Medicine, 1909-1948 (Box 13, Folder 110)
    Declined request to finance building for Academy and participation in other special drives. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed $7,500 to polio drive, 1928; $5,000, 1931; $1,000, 1931. RBF financed conference on Etiology of Mental Disease. Booklet, "Self-Forgiveness" by T. V. Smith. John D. Rockefeller 3rd gift of $95,000 to Museum of Health. Martha Baird Rockefeller's pledge toward publication of Dr. J. Marshall Hoag's book on osteopathy, 1961. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller.
    143
  - New York Academy of Medicine, 1953-1961 (Box 13, Folder 111)
    Declined request to finance building for Academy and participation in other special drives. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed $7,500 to polio drive, 1928; $5,000, 1931; $1,000, 1931. Rockefeller Brothers Fund financed conference on Etiology of Mental Disease. Booklet, "Self-Forgiveness" by T. V. Smith. John D. Rockefeller 3rd gift of $95,000 to Museum of Health. Martha Baird Rockefeller's pledge toward publication of Dr. J. Marshall Hoag's book on osteopathy, 1961. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller.
  - New York Academy of Osteopathy/Foundation for Research of the Academy, 1952-1961 (Box 13, Folder 112)
    Promote research, provide information. Laurance S. Rockefeller gift; Nelson A. Rockefeller; Abby Rockefeller Mauz contributions. Correspondents include W. Kenneth Riland, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    143.1
- Polio
  - Polio - Georgia Warm Springs Foundation, 1928-1954 (Box 14, Folder 113)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions to Warm Springs; declination to participate in President's Birthday Ball. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Franklin D. Roosevelt, Raymond B. Fosdick.
    171
  - Polio - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis/National Foundation, 1937-1949 (Box 14, Folder 114)
    Family showed only nominal interest in National Foundation program; Foundation secrecy about finances unacceptable to Rockefeller interests. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave directly to Warm Springs, Georgia, 1928-1936. Nelson A. Rockefeller contributions to Foundation, 1959-1961. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Basil O'Conner.
    171A
  - Polio - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis/National Foundation, 1950-1955 (Box 14, Folder 115)
  - Polio - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis/National Foundation, 1956-1961 (Box 14, Folder 116)
  - Polio - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis/National Foundation - Printed Material and Clippings, 1938-1961 (Box 14, Folder 117)
  - Polio - Sister Kenny Foundation, 1944-1960 (Box 15, Folder 118)
    To promote Kenny method of treatment. Report on organization. No family contributions.
    171.1
  - Polio - Sister Kenny Foundation, 1944-1960 (Box 15, Folder 0118A)
  - Polio - Physical Rehabilitation Foundation, 1945-1949 (Box 15, Folder 119)
    Betsey Barton begins foundation dedicated to studying and teaching methods of treatment for physically handicapped. No contributions made. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Betsey Barton.
    171.2
- Social Hygiene
  - Social Hygiene - American Social Hygiene Association - Sex Education Work - Dr. Exner, 1920, 1923 (Box 15, Folder 120)
    Becomes American Social Health Association. Operation of Association; increasing war work; John D. Rockefeller Jr.'s support. W. F. Snow's informal report to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Tribute to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for contributions to work of association, make him Honorary Life Member. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions to war work. Name changed to American Social Health Association. Dr. Snow's death. Correspondents include W. F. Snow, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William H. Zinsser.
    35
  - Social Hygiene - American Social Hygiene Association - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Contributions, 1915-1940 (Box 15, Folder 121)
    Becomes American Social Health Association. John D. Rockefeller Jr.'s letters of appeals for aid to A.S.H.A. List of contributors who responded to appeals. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s assistance in finding chairman for 1937 campaign; contribution toward 1940 VD campaign. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., W. F. Snow, Raymond B. Fosdick, W. Lyman.
  - Social Hygiene - American Social Hygiene Association - Dr. Snow's Salary, 1919-1939 (Box 15, Folder 122)
    Becomes American Social Health Association. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. guaranteed Snow $12,000 annual income; association paid him $10,000; Jr. made up difference, 1922-1924. After 1924 Snow's income was over $12,000. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. replaced salary guarantee with $2,000 annual payment to ease retirement. Correspondents include W. F. Snow, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Social Hygiene - American Social Hygiene Association - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Solicitations, 1915(?)-1922 (Box 15, Folder 123)
    Becomes American Social Health Association.
  - Social Hygiene - American Social Hygiene Association - Bureau of Social Hygiene Pledges, 1919-1928 (Box 15, Folder 124)
    Becomes American Social Health Association. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. has Bureau of Social Hygiene (BSH) make pledge to American Social Hygiene Association (ASHA); in return the two organizations were to cooperate closely in their work. ASHA officers investigated vice conditions in New York; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. financed it, through BSH, at $5,000 per quarter until 1928, when arrangement was replaced by non-recurring gift to ASHA. (BSH simultaneously being reorganized.) Regular pledges of BSH to ASHA's general work. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, William F. Snow, Charles O. Heydt, Lawrence B. Dunham.
  - Social Hygiene - American Social Hygiene Association - 1942 Appeal to USO (Box 15, Folder 125)
    Becomes American Social Health Association. Arthur W. Packard assists ASHA in preparing appeal to United Service Organization for gift toward work of ASHA; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. follows negotiations. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Social Hygiene - American Social Health Association/American Social Hygiene Association, 1919-1939 (Box 16, Folder 126)
  - Social Hygiene - American Social Health Association/American Social Hygiene Association, 1940-1949 (Box 16, Folder 127)
  - Social Hygiene - American Social Health Association/American Social Hygiene Association, 1950-1951 (Box 16, Folder 128)
  - Social Hygiene - International Committee for Mental Health, 1948-1960 (Box 16, Folder 129)
    To hold an International Congress on Mental Health; RBF contributions. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, June Bingham.
    35.1
  - Social Hygiene - International Committee for Mental Health, 1948-1960 (Box 16, Folder 0129A)
  - Social Hygiene - New York Social Hygiene Society/American Society of Sanitary and Moral Prophylaxis, 1910-1925 (Box 16, Folder 130)
    Rockefeller contributions. Dr. Ekner's sex education work. Society absorbed by American Social Hygiene Association. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., J. D. Greene, W. F. Snow.
  - Social Hygiene - New York Society for the Suppression of Vice/Society to Maintain Public Decency, 1899-1923 (Box 17, Folder 131)
    Rockefeller contributions to Society, 1894-1931, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and John D. Rockefeller, Sr. Frederick T. Gates questions efficiency of Anthony Comstock. Disapproval of changing aims of society (reflected in new name), ending of contribution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Antony Comstock, J. S. Summer.
    35.3
  - Social Hygiene - New York Society for the Suppression of Vice/Society to Maintain Public Decency, 1924-1949 (Box 17, Folder 132)
- Tuberculosis
  - Tuberculosis - National Tuberculosis Association, 1904-1957 (Box 17, Folder 133)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. early contributions; later request declined. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson.
    71
  - Tuberculosis - Treatment, 1921-1953 (Box 17, Folder 134)
    Suggested cures for tuberculosis.
    71.1
  - Tuberculosis - Treatment - House of Rest, 1945-1955 (Box 17, Folder 135)